<Sections>
    <Section>
        <Header></Header>
        <ImagePath></ImagePath>
        <Paragraph>
        The time that I spent in La Mauricie National Park allowed me to establish a deeper connection to the natural elements of the region but, from the onset, I was excited to visit Trois-Rivières because I assumed that it was the city where I’d get better acquainted with the social, economic, and historical side of Mauricie. 
        It turns out, that’s exactly what happened, since Trois-Rivières is the largest city in the area, and was actually the second permanent settlement in New France after Quebec City. 
        Trois-Rivières is Canada’s oldest industrial city, and that history has continued up until the present day. I think it’s a mistake to go to a city like Trois-Rivières and wonder why it doesn’t look and feel exactly like Quebec City. They’ve both got important, separate histories, and the appearance of the city reflects that. Personally, I just felt honoured to be able to dive further into my nation’s history, and to have an open mind as to what I’d experience here. 
        In the end, I was really nicely surprised by Trois-Rivières. I visited some top-notch restaurants, spent time in a historical centre with beauty that rivals much of what I’ve seen in cities in Europe, strolled through some pleasant parks, stayed at a brand new hotel that should serve the city very well, and a whole lot more which I’ll get into below. 
        With everything that has gone on in recent memory, I believe we’re entering an age of travel and tourism where we’re going to have a renewed vigor to explore places that perhaps weren’t on our bucket-list prior. I know that that’s certainly the case with my Ontario site, where I’ve spent time exploring places that I’d overlooked before, and I’m usually very pleasantly surprised by what I find. And on that note, I’m going to run through how you can best explore Trois-Rivières if you decide that you too want to add it to your Canadian exploration bucket-list! 
        </Paragraph>
    </Section>
    <Section>
        <Header>About Trois-Rivières, Quebec</Header>
        <ImagePath>D:\source\repos\MyBlog\Database\Images\old-town-trois-rivieres.jpg</ImagePath>
        <Paragraph>
        At the confluence of the Saint-Maurice and Saint Lawrence rivers is where you’ll find Trois-Rivières. It’s approximately halfway between Montreal and Quebec City, and it’s the most populous city in the Mauricie Region with a population of just under 150,000. 
        The city’s name, which of course means “three rivers,” is apparently a reference to the fact that the Saint-Maurice River has three mouths at the Saint Lawrence River. I  will admit that I also heard that, in the early 17th century, there was some confusion with the two islands in the river that made it look like there were three rivers converging, and that’s where the name actually came from, but who knows?!
        For fun, I often like to look at what the name for a city’s inhabitants are. For example, being from Toronto, I’m technically a Torontonian. Well, I think Trois-Rivières takes the cake for coolest name for a group of city inhabitants. They’re known as “Trifluviens.” 
        Trois-Rivières is also officially the “poetry capital of Quebec.” I noticed myself that there poems that were posted up in the city, including hundreds that were hanging from wire in a local park. I also happened across a Q&amp;A with a local poet in a small coffee shop. 
        The city’s history is an important one in Canada. It was the site of major battles during the Seven Years’ War and the American Revolutionary War, as well as an epicentre before that for the fur trade. I get the sense that Trois-Rivières is now keen to write its next chapter. They’ve invested big money in tech, clean energy, and tourism, and it seems to me like there’s never been a better time to go and witness the city’s growth and transformation. 
        Here are some of the top things to do in Trois-Rivières!
        </Paragraph>
    </Section>
    <Section>
        <Header>What to do in Trois-Rivières on Your Next Visit</Header>
        <ImagePath>D:\source\repos\MyBlog\Database\Images\historic-trois-rivieres-quebec.jpg</ImagePath>
        <Paragraph>
        There’s quite a bit to do here, and it’s well suited to a weekend visit, especially if there’s a sizeable concert or performance in town (which happens more than you’d think since, as I mentioned above, it’s smack dab in the middle of Quebec City and Montreal). 
        VISIT THE VIEILLE PRISON DE TROIS-RIVIÈRES (OLD PRISON OF TROIS-RIVIÈRES)
        The Vieille prison de Trois-Rivières holds the title of Canada’s longest operating detention centre. The prison officially opened in 1822, and it was ultimately closed in 1986, which means it was operational for more than 160 years. Since it didn’t close all that long ago, tours of the facility are often led by former inmates. What really adds to the experience of the visit is that the building remains largely unchanged from its original design and layout, so you can get a clear sense of what it would have been like to be incarcerated there. 
        They’ve got plenty of innovative programming running at this old prison. Most notably, an escape room style game, as well as a role-playing activity where you get to be a member of a jury. You can find out more about all that, as well as hours of operation for your visit, right here. 
        You should also consider visiting the Musée Pop which is connected to the Vieille prison de Trois-Rivières. Its main goal is to examine and showcase Quebec’s culture over the years and in the present day. 
        CATCH A PERFORMANCE AT L'AMPHITHÉÂTRE COGECO (COGECO AMPHITHEATRE)
        This arrival of this world class amphitheatre has been a game-changer for the city of Trois-Rivières. In the summer months, it’s very much wide open and integrated with the outdoor surroundings, and from November to May, the amphitheatre transforms into an intimate performance centre which is closed off with a smaller selection of seats. In 2016, the Cogeco Amphitheatre was actually one of 12 recipients of the Governor General’’s Media in Architecture. 
        At full capacity, it holds about 15000 people. The whole project was actually spurred by a desire to do something special to celebrate the 375th anniversary of the city back in 2009. They decided on this project in 2011, started building in 2013, and were finished by 2015. 
        Some top-flight artists have already stopped here, most notably the likes of Celine Dion, ZZ Top, Steppenwolf, Styx and Buddy Guy. You can find a list of upcoming shows here. 
        </Paragraph>
    </Section>
    <Section>
        <Header>TREAT YOURSELF TO A GREAT HOTEL</Header>
        <ImagePath>D:\source\repos\MyBlog\Database\Images\delta-trois-rivieres.jpg</ImagePath>
        <Paragraph>
        Part of what made Trois-Rivières so easy to explore was that I was staying at the Delta Hotels Trois Rivieres Conference Centre, which is located right downtown. They’re located one block from the St. Lawrence River, quite near to the shops, bars and restaurants that you’ll want to pop-into during your visit to Trois-Rivières. 
        They’re also very close to the Amphithéâtre Cogeco, so if you’re going for a concert there, this might be a nice place to rest your head. The hotel looks and feels brand new and ready to host people. In fact, they’ve got a 55,000 square foot conference centre attached to the hotel!
        I had a guest room there with a king bed, and it was a modern room that offered views of the St. Lawrence right from my window. In the morning, I had breakfast at Le Brasier 1908, and it was excellent. The service there was impeccable, and that actually holds true for the staff from the whole hotel. 
        I was very pleased with my stay there, and would happily stay at the Detla Trois-Rivières again. 
        </Paragraph>
    </Section>
    <Section>
        <Header>Go out on the town</Header>
        <ImagePath>D:\source\repos\MyBlog\Database\Images\trois-rivieres-nightlife.jpg</ImagePath>
        <Paragraph>
        I felt I got a good grasp for just how fun (and delicious) this city could be by visiting some of its top restaurants and bars. 
        One restaurant that I’d strongly recommend is called Le Temps d’une Pinte, and it’s basically what happens when inventive tapas converge with creative microbrewing. The atmosphere was stellar, to the point where I felt I could have stayed there all night. Excellent food and drink! Other restaurants that you’ll want to keep on your radar include Le Sacristain (probably the consensus number one restaurant), Le Buck, and Le Poivre Noir. 
        In terms of going out, I’d recommend that you head straight for Rue des Forges, and then see what suits you. You can see quite easily from the outside which places are more about dance, which places are more about cocktails, and which places are more about beer. It’s quite literally a party street with something for everyone. 
        Famous spots on the street include Le Temple, Le Bureau de Poste, Le Roof Top, Le Trèfle and many more. Honestly, it’s a good spot to just do a little exploration and let you preferences guide you! 
        </Paragraph>
    </Section>
    <Section>
        <Header>Trois-Rivières Awaits!</Header>
        <ImagePath></ImagePath>
        <Paragraph>
        I sincerely hope the information will help guide you on your future adventures in Trois-Rivières. Trois-Rivières is a city where history buffs, outdoorsy people, and bar hoppers can all be happy, because there’s a little something for everyone. Montreal and Quebec City are tremendous cities, of that there is no question, but I do think Trois-Rivières deserves a little more love, and that’s what this article is all about. 
        If you do head that way, to catch a concert or a hockey game, let me know how you enjoyed it below. Safe travels, my friends!
        </Paragraph>
    </Section>
</Sections>